### **Nigel David**

Residence: Austin, TX

Email: not.nigel@protonmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Enthusiastic and well-organized Java EE developer with 3+ years of experience. Eager to join a team to bring in top-class Java development and problem-solving skills. Recent experience as a scrum master, system engineer, and developer for AT&T telecommunication software.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**IBM** 

October 2013 – Present

# Software Defined Networks – GUI Portal, AT&T Account Developer

April 2016 – Present

Applied relevant technical skills to deliver specifications, program changes, unit test scripts, and documentation for AT&T's SDN web application. Provided view components using HTML, JS, and the DHTMLX (JS, AJAX, HTML) framework. Provided service level REST APIs, DAOs, data manipulation, and unit testing using Java, Spring, and MariaDB. Mitigated security vulnerabilities and code quality issues using the HP Fortify Scan and SonarQube. Modularized components to create faster builds and independent deployments. Reviewed pull requests for design principles and memory and speed efficiency.

<u>Tech Stack:</u> Java 8, Spring, Spring Boot, jUnit 4, Maven, xQuery, JSP, JavaScript (ES5), DHTMLX, Tomcat 8.0, MariaDB

Ops Stack: SWM (internal), Jenkins, Docker

<u>Tools Used:</u> IntelliJ, Eclipse, Sublime Text 3, Oracle VitrualBox, Rational Team Concert, Bitbucket, JIRA, SourceTree, XMLSpy, MySQL Workbench, Postman, GitBash

#### AT&T Account Scrum Master

June 2014 – March 2016

Served as a leader for scrum teams to ensure Agile methodologies and principles are adhered to throughout iterations, prevent interference from outside the Scrum team, and provide assistance to the team when potential blockers are present. Organize and facilitate sprint planning, daily stand-up meetings, reviews, retrospectives, release planning, demos and other Scrum related meetings. Coordinate deliverables across iterations and releases and act as a liaison between the Product Owners and the team.

# Universal Service Request Platform, AT&T System Engineer

October 2013 - June 2015

Created system requirements and documentation that represents the customer's vision for AT&T's Universal Service Request Platform. Used logical data analysis and design principles to coordinate requirements with developers and other engineers to enhance and maintain the system.

Tools used: Word, Excel macros, VIM, Eclipse, XML Spy, iRise, Sybase, ReqPro, RallyDev

#### **EDUCATION**

### Texas State University,

August 2008 - May 2013

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Minor in Applied Mathematics

Relevant Courses: Software Engineering, Networks, Parallel Programming, Human Factors, Object Oriented Programming, Computer Architecture, and fundamental programming courses

#### **SKILLS**

- Scrum Master Experience on Agile and Blended Agile projects
- Practiced System Engineer providing maintenance services for software
- Telecommunications Industry Experience with AT&T ordering and provisioning systems
- Skilled with the MS Office Suite: Word, Excel, Visio, PowerPoint
- Experienced with building web applications with the LAMP stack
- Intermediate skill with C, C++, Java, JS
- Basic skill with CUDA, AngularJS, PHP
- Basic knowledge of architecture exploitations, parallel approaches, and optimizations
- Knowledge of database constructs, schema design, and SQL
- Effective communication in a business and technical environment
- Skilled with design document creation and technical writing